<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-14T00:02:06+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Magical Musings</title><subtitle>Ramblings of an aspiring Wizard.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Drawmij’s Instant Summons</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/instant-summons/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drawmij’s Instant Summons" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-instant-summons</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/instant-summons/">&lt;p&gt;You touch an object weighing 10 pounds or less whose longest dimension is 6 feet or less. The spell leaves an invisible mark on its surface and invisibly inscribes the name of the item on the sapphire you use as the material component. Each time you cast this spell, you must use a different sapphire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At any time thereafter, you can use your action to speak the item’s name and crush the sapphire. The item instantly appears in your hand regardless of physical or planar distances, and the spell ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If another creature is holding or carrying the item, crushing the sapphire doesn’t transport the item to you, but instead you learn who the creature possessing the object is and roughly where that creature is located at that moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dispel magic or a similar effect successfully applied to the sapphire ends this spell’s effect.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">You touch an object weighing 10 pounds or less whose longest dimension is 6 feet or less. The spell leaves an invisible mark on its surface and invisibly inscribes the name of the item on the sapphire you use as the material component. Each time you cast this spell, you must use a different sapphire.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forbiddance</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/forbiddance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forbiddance" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-forbiddance</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/forbiddance/">&lt;p&gt;You create a ward against magical travel that protects up to 40,000 square feet of floor space to a height of 30 feet above the floor. For the duration, creatures can’t teleport into the area or use portals, such as those created by the gate spell, to enter the area. The spell proofs the area against planar travel, and therefore prevents creatures from accessing the area by way of the Astral Plane, Ethereal Plane, Feywild, Shadowfell, or the plane shift spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, the spell damages types of creatures that you choose when you cast it. Choose one or more of the following: celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead. When a chosen creature enters the spell’s area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, the creature takes 5d10 radiant or necrotic damage (your choice when you cast this spell).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you cast this spell, you can designate a password. A creature that speaks the password as it enters the area takes no damage from the spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spell’s area can’t overlap with the area of another forbiddance spell. If you cast forbiddance every day for 30 days in the same location, the spell lasts until it is dispelled, and the material components are consumed on the last casting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Cleric" /><summary type="html">You create a ward against magical travel that protects up to 40,000 square feet of floor space to a height of 30 feet above the floor. For the duration, creatures can’t teleport into the area or use portals, such as those created by the gate spell, to enter the area. The spell proofs the area against planar travel, and therefore prevents creatures from accessing the area by way of the Astral Plane, Ethereal Plane, Feywild, Shadowfell, or the plane shift spell.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Flesh to Stone</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/flesh-to-stone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flesh to Stone" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-flesh-to-stone</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/flesh-to-stone/">&lt;p&gt;You attempt to turn one creature that you can see within range into stone. If the target’s body is made of flesh, the creature must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it is restrained as its flesh begins to harden. On a successful save, the creature isn’t affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A creature restrained by this spell must make another Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns. If it successfully saves against this spell three times, the spell ends. If it fails its saves three times, it is turned to stone and subjected to the petrified condition for the duration. The successes and failures don’t need to be consecutive; keep track of both until the target collects three of a kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the creature is physically broken while petrified, it suffers from similar deformities if it reverts to its original state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you maintain your concentration on this spell for the entire possible duration, the creature is turned to stone until the effect is removed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Warlock" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">You attempt to turn one creature that you can see within range into stone. If the target’s body is made of flesh, the creature must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it is restrained as its flesh begins to harden. On a successful save, the creature isn’t affected.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Find the Path</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/find-the-path/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Find the Path" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-find-the-path</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/find-the-path/">&lt;p&gt;This spell allows you to find the shortest, most direct physical route to a specific fixed location that you are familiar with on the same plane of existence. If you name a destination on another plane of existence, a destination that moves (such as a mobile fortress), or a destination that isn’t specific (such as “a green dragon’s lair”), the spell fails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the duration, as long as you are on the same plane of existence as the destination, you know how far it is and in what direction it lies. While you are traveling there, whenever you are presented with a choice of paths along the way, you automatically determine which path is the shortest and most direct route (but not necessarily the safest route) to the destination.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Bard" /><category term="Cleric" /><category term="Druid" /><summary type="html">This spell allows you to find the shortest, most direct physical route to a specific fixed location that you are familiar with on the same plane of existence. If you name a destination on another plane of existence, a destination that moves (such as a mobile fortress), or a destination that isn’t specific (such as “a green dragon’s lair”), the spell fails.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eyebite</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/eyebite/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eyebite" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-eyebite</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/eyebite/">&lt;p&gt;For the spell’s duration, your eyes become an inky void imbued with dread power. One creature of your choice within 60 feet of you that you can see must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be affected by one of the following effects of your choice for the duration. On each of your turns until the spell ends, you can use your action to target another creature but can’t target a creature again if it has succeeded on a saving throw against this casting of eyebite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Asleep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The target falls unconscious. It wakes up if it takes any damage or if another creature uses its action to shake the sleeper awake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panicked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The target is frightened of you. On each of its turns, the frightened creature must take the Dash action and move away from you by the safest and shortest available route, unless there is nowhere to move. If the target moves to a place at least 60 feet away from you where it can no longer see you, this effect ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sickened.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; The target has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks. At the end of each of its turns, it can make another Wisdom saving throw. If it succeeds, the effect ends.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Bard" /><category term="Sorcerer" /><category term="Warlock" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">For the spell’s duration, your eyes become an inky void imbued with dread power. One creature of your choice within 60 feet of you that you can see must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be affected by one of the following effects of your choice for the duration. On each of your turns until the spell ends, you can use your action to target another creature but can’t target a creature again if it has succeeded on a saving throw against this casting of eyebite.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Druid Grove</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/druid-grove/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Druid Grove" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-druid-grove</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/druid-grove/">&lt;p&gt;You invoke the spirits of nature to protect an area outdoors or underground. The area can be as small as a 30-foot cube or as large as a 90-foot cube. Buildings and other structures are excluded from the affected area. If you cast this spell in the same area every day for a year, the spell lasts until dispelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The spell creates the following effects within the area. When you cast this spell, you can specify creatures as friends who are immune to the effects. You can also specify a password that, when spoken aloud, makes the speaker immune to these effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire warded area radiates magic. A dispel magic cast on the area, if successful, removes only one of the following effects, not the entire area. That spell’s caster chooses which effect to end. Only when all its effects are gone is this spell dispelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solid Fog.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You can fill any number of 5-foot squares on the ground with thick fog, making them heavily obscured. The fog reaches 10 feet high. In addition, every foot of movement through the fog costs 2 extra feet. To a creature immune to this effect, the fog obscures nothing and looks like soft mist, with motes of green light floating in the air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grasping Undergrowth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You can fill any number of 5-foot squares on the ground that aren’t filled with fog with grasping weeds and vines, as if they were affected by an entangle spell. To a creature immune to this effect, the weeds and vines feel soft and reshape themselves to serve as temporary seats or beds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grove Guardians.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You can animate up to four trees in the area, causing them to uproot themselves from the ground. These trees have the same statistics as an awakened tree, which appears in the Monster Manual, except they can’t speak, and their bark is covered with druidic symbols. If any creature not immune to this effect enters the warded area, the grove guardians fight until they have driven off or slain the intruders. The grove guardians also obey your spoken commands (no action required by you) that you issue while in the area. If you don’t give them commands and no intruders are present, the grove guardians do nothing. The grove guardians can’t leave the warded area. When the spell ends, the magic animating them disappears, and the trees take root again if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Additional Spell Effect.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; You can place your choice of one of the following magical effects within the warded area:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A constant gust of wind in two locations of your choice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spike growth in one location of your choice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wind wall in two locations of your choice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To a creature immune to this effect, the winds are a fragrant, gentle breeze, and the area of spike growth is harmless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Druid" /><summary type="html">You invoke the spirits of nature to protect an area outdoors or underground. The area can be as small as a 30-foot cube or as large as a 90-foot cube. Buildings and other structures are excluded from the affected area. If you cast this spell in the same area every day for a year, the spell lasts until dispelled.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Disintegrate</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/disintegrate/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Disintegrate" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-disintegrate</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/disintegrate/">&lt;p&gt;A thin green ray springs from your pointing finger to a target that you can see within range. The target can be a creature, an object, or a creation of magical force, such as the wall created by wall of force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A creature targeted by this spell must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the target takes 10d6 + 40 force damage. The target is disintegrated if this damage leaves it with 0 hit points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A disintegrated creature and everything it is wearing and carrying, except magic items, are reduced to a pile of fine gray dust. The creature can be restored to life only by means of a true resurrection or a wish spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This spell automatically disintegrates a Large or smaller nonmagical object or a creation of magical force. If the target is a Huge or larger object or creation of force, this spell disintegrates a 10-foot-cube portion of it. A magic item is unaffected by this spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level or higher, the damage increases by 3d6 for each slot level above 6th.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Sorcerer" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">A thin green ray springs from your pointing finger to a target that you can see within range. The target can be a creature, an object, or a creation of magical force, such as the wall created by wall of force.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Create Undead</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/create-undead/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Create Undead" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-create-undead</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/create-undead/">&lt;p&gt;You can cast this spell only at night. Choose up to three corpses of Medium or Small humanoids within range. Each corpse becomes a ghoul under your control. (The DM has game statistics for these creatures.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a bonus action on each of your turns, you can mentally command any creature you animated with this spell if the creature is within 120 feet of you (if you control multiple creatures, you can command any or all of them at the same time, issuing the same command to each one). You decide what action the creature will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you can issue a general command, such as to guard a particular chamber or corridor. If you issue no commands, the creature only defends itself against hostile creatures. Once given an order, the creature continues to follow it until its task is complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creature is under your control for 24 hours, after which it stops obeying any command you have given it. To maintain control of the creature for another 24 hours, you must cast this spell on the creature before the current 24-hour period ends. This use of the spell reasserts your control over up to three creatures you have animated with this spell, rather than animating new ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;At Higher Levels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; When you cast this spell using a 7th-level spell slot, you can animate or reassert control over four ghouls. When you cast this spell using an 8th-level spell slot, you can animate or reassert control over five ghouls or two ghasts or wights. When you cast this spell using a 9th-level spell slot, you can animate or reassert control over six ghouls, three ghasts or wights, or two mummies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Cleric" /><category term="Warlock" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">You can cast this spell only at night. Choose up to three corpses of Medium or Small humanoids within range. Each corpse becomes a ghoul under your control. (The DM has game statistics for these creatures.)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Create Homonculus</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/create-homonculus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Create Homonculus" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-create-homonculus</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/create-homonculus/">&lt;p&gt;While speaking an intricate incantation, you cut yourself with a jewel-encrusted dagger, taking 2d4 piercing damage that can’t be reduced in any way. You then drip your blood on the spell’s other components and touch them, transforming them into a special construct called a homunculus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The statistics of the homunculus are in the Monster Manual. It is your faithful companion, and it dies if you die. Whenever you finish a long rest, you can spend up to half your Hit Dice if the homunculus is on the same plane of existence as you. When you do so, roll each die and add your Constitution modifier to it. Your hit point maximum is reduced by the total, and the homunculus’s hit point maximum and current hit points are both increased by it. This process can reduce you to no lower than 1 hit point, and the change to your and the homunculus’s hit points ends when you finish your next long rest. The reduction to your hit point maximum can’t be removed by any means before then, except by the homunculus’s death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can have only one homunculus at a time. If you cast this spell while your homunculus lives, the spell fails.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">While speaking an intricate incantation, you cut yourself with a jewel-encrusted dagger, taking 2d4 piercing damage that can’t be reduced in any way. You then drip your blood on the spell’s other components and touch them, transforming them into a special construct called a homunculus.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Contingency</title><link href="/spells/sixth-level/contingency/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Contingency" /><published>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2020-10-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/spells/sixth-level/spells-6-contingency</id><content type="html" xml:base="/spells/sixth-level/contingency/">&lt;p&gt;Choose a spell of 5th level or lower that you can cast, that has a casting time of 1 action, and that can target you. You cast that spell—called the contingent spell—as part of casting contingency, expending spell slots for both, but the contingent spell doesn’t come into effect. Instead, it takes effect when a certain circumstance occurs. You describe that circumstance when you cast the two spells. For example, a contingency cast with water breathing might stipulate that water breathing comes into effect when you are engulfed in water or a similar liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contingent spell takes effect immediately after the circumstance is met for the first time, whether or not you want it to, and then contingency ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contingent spell takes effect only on you, even if it can normally target others. You can use only one contingency spell at a time. If you cast this spell again, the effect of another contingency spell on you ends. Also, contingency ends on you if its material component is ever not on your person.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Spells" /><category term="Sixth Level" /><category term="Wizard" /><summary type="html">Choose a spell of 5th level or lower that you can cast, that has a casting time of 1 action, and that can target you. You cast that spell—called the contingent spell—as part of casting contingency, expending spell slots for both, but the contingent spell doesn’t come into effect. Instead, it takes effect when a certain circumstance occurs. You describe that circumstance when you cast the two spells. For example, a contingency cast with water breathing might stipulate that water breathing comes into effect when you are engulfed in water or a similar liquid.</summary></entry></feed>